From far mist, from calm lakes beyond the commune's hills comes a rustle: Maria is coming. 
I walk the endless fields, transiting the passes and where the burial mound, I am leaning on a lonely deserted cliff. 
I look into the distance.–Then one after the other, the thoughts are dancing around me, like Amazon girls. 
Everything disappears then... 
Mystery riders are flying, staggering rhythmically, towards the spurs, and the day is dying down; 
the road is running in graves and beyond it–silent steppe... 
I lift up my eyelashes and remember... truly my mother is an archetype of that incredible Maria, who stands on the verge of unknown ages. 
My mother is endless innocence, solemn sadness and infinite kindness. (So well do I remember it!). 
And my unbearable pain and my intolerable suffering are warming in the sacred candles before this ambrosial and sad vision.

Mother says that I (her restless son) have sorely tortured myself... 
And then I take her lovely head with the silver that covers her hair and silently put it on my chest... 
Beyond the window dewy mornings were coming and pearls were falling down. Incredible days were passing. 
Somewhere from far the dark forest made their way wanderers and by a blue well, where the roads flew apart, 
where a rogue crosses, they were stopped. A young tanning was it.